

Mehmet Akif Tütüncü

Senior Software Engineer

- Amsterdam, Netherlands

♠ https://akif.dev

makiftutuncu

in makiftutuncu

y makiftutuncu

I'm mainly focused on backend. I have more than 9 years of professional experience in software industry. I've worked with companies around the world and conducted consulting/training. I have extensive JVM knowledge and proficiency in Scala, Java, Kotlin using both object-oriented and functional programming. I have skills in CI/CD, testing, databases, cloud applications, micro-services. I am a fan of open-source software.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer @ iO

(Dec 2022 - Present)

Before joining a client project as a consultant, I acted as a developer advocate. I co-organized a workshop, wrote on company blog, attended recruitment interviews/reviews and worked on improving the hiring process.

https://iodigital.com

Senior Software Engineer @ Scalac

(Nov 2021 - Oct 2022)

I worked with Conduktor as a consultant. I migrated part of their legacy Java API to a new Scala service. It included an automated mechanism to check for correctness. Then I worked on admin features of Conduktor Platform, spanning multiple Conduktor products.

https://scalac.io

Software Engineer @ Numbrs

(Nov 2020 - Oct 2021)

I worked in Personal Finance Management team. I was responsible for developing new features to Numbrs app backend.

https://www.numbrs.com

Senior Software Engineer @ sahibinden.com

(Aug 2019 - Nov 2020)

I worked in the search team. I usually dealt with search, promotions and categories domains. I also took the lead on automating the process of updating location and geo data.

https://sahibinden.com

Software Engineer @ VNGRS

(May 2017 - Aug 2019)

I consulted in multiple projects. In MAF Properties team, I worked in the kick-off process for their latest product. In Beam team, I helped migrate and maintain a mobile payment system. In Socrata team, I helped design, develop and maintain multiple backend projects.

https://vngrs.com

Software Engineer @ Linovi

(Oct 2013 - Oct 2016)

I started as part-time here. Then I joined Shazam team full-time. I had varying tasks from developing features, fixing bugs, writing automated tests to maintaining projects.

Android Developer @ iDivino

(Aug 2012 - Aug 2013)

I worked part-time on developing games for preschool children.

EDUCATION

Izmir Institute of Technology

(Aug 2009 - Jun 2014)

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Engineering

Education in English, focused on software, started my career halfway through with internships and part-time positions

SKILLS

Frameworks/Libraries/Tools

Akka, AWS, cats, circe, Docker, Elasticsearch, git, Gradle, http4s, JUnit, Kafka, Play Framework, Quill, SBT, ScalaTest, Spring Framework, tapir, ZIO

Databases

Cassandra, DynamoDB, Firebase, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis

Progamming Languages

Go, Java, Kotlin, Scala

Techniques

Agile, CI/CD, DDD, Kanban, Microservices, SCRUM, TDD

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Effect

Functional effect library in Scala https://github.com/makiftutuncu/effect Scala, Functional Effect, Error Handling

Muezzin

Android application and server https://github.com/makiftutuncu/Muezzin

Scala, Java, Play Framework, PostgreSQL, Anorm, Akka

Bookstore

A project demonstrating automated testing on backend https://github.com/makiftutuncu/bookstore

Scala, Finch, ScalaTest, Postman, Docker, Flyway, Doobie, PostgreSQL

k-retry

Naive retry implementation

https://github.com/makiftutuncu/k-retry

Kotlin, JUnit

TALKS AND PRESENTATIONS

Things I Learned Building a Functional Effect System

Functional Scala 2022

https://youtu.be/ZNB2epqQhc8

Dealing with Errors on JVM with e

ScalaUA 2020

https://youtu.be/HAQZtTZae_Q

Kotlin for Backends

sahibinden.com D2D

https://github.com/makiftutuncu/kotlin-for-backends

Typeclass 101

VNGRS Lightning Talks

https://youtu.be/jPiM9uBHpWI

Testing Web Backends With Scala

Test Hive

https://youtu.be/QnK8pyGUOac

Working Remotely From Turkey

Interview with DevTech Community

https://youtu.be/VbvIIcR-JYg

LANGUAGES

Turkish

Native

English

Professional

CERTIFICATIONS

Complete Guide to Elasticsearch

Udemy

(Jun 2020) AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate (May 2018)

Amazon

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Kodluyoruz

(Dec 2020 - Jan 2021)

Izmir Institute of Technology

(Jan 2013 - Apr 2013)

Instructor

I gave introduction to Scala and functional programming I gave Android lectures in student club at my university.

lectures.

Instructor